Welcome. My name is Buko and in this
video we'll talk about how to build
Microsoft Copilot Studio agents using
business central data. What is Copilot
Studio? Copilot Studio is a part of
Power Platform, a product that allows
you to build conversational experiences
and agents connected to various data.
And that data could be coming from
business central using copilot studio.
You have option to build a full copilot
studio uh agent uh but also a light
experience available in Microsoft 365
copilot chat and then more advanced um
tooling for pro developers and all those
agents are built on AI foundation models
use tools and knowledge to access data
and present user experience through
orchestrator.
When you build an agent using Business
Central data, building an agent in
Copilot Studio allows you to connect to
data through the Power Platform
connector and that connects to our APIs
or through the new MCP server that also
connects to our APIs.
So what is that MCP server? Model
context protocol or MCP is an open
protocol that allows all AI systems to
communicate with the various business
applications in a standard way. It's
very easy then to connect to to data
using this protocol.
Let's show that in a demo.
Here I am in Copilot Studio and I would
like to build a new agent. So I select
new agent button.
and I uh present a description. So here
a copilot studio
uh built-in copilot helps me build an
agent. So in those instructions I can uh
I I specify that it is about researching
laptop options and that I have data in
business central where uh my items uh
represent laptops and this is based on
item category code called laptop.
That is all which is needed to build an
agent.
Copilot studio now is processing data
and building the agent for me suggesting
options
in business central I can see that I
have items if I filter by laptops I can
also show that the filter built is built
using item category called laptop so I
have some laptop laptops for my
employees as a noninventory items in
business central
also in business central I can go to MC
MCP configurations. So there is a new
page in called MCP configurations where
I define a specific configurations
exposing this API with items in a read
only mode. Very simple example and I
activate this particular configuration.
Now in copilot studio my uh agent is
ready. As you can see, instructions have
been added and all I need to do is to
add the tool which is basically the
Microsoft Business Central MCP server.
So I select it from here. Uh I use uh
model contract protocol tab and then I
need to configure it. So I added that
already and I configure it to be
connected to specific environment and uh
MCP configuration.
This is all what is needed. I can test
this uh agent here directly in copilot
studio or I can publish it to different
channels and those channels um represent
where the agent will live. In my case, I
would uh use teams and Microsoft 365
copilot because I would like to publish
this agent on Microsoft 365 copilot.
Let's switch to Microsoft 365 copilot
chat and I you can see my laptop agent
agent already there. I can select one of
the predefined queries or prompts and um
ask the laptop agent to provide me data
from Business Central. That data is
coming from Business Central with
various available laptops. I can also
ask about for instance screen
resolution. So these are all predefined
prompts generated by copilot studio but
I can of course edit it as an outer of
the agent and I can add some additional
prompts like for instance ask for
laptops that are uh more suited for
remote work. The data that um the agent
uses here is coming from the internet
plus business central and all the
specifications for those laptops are are
presented and ready for me. It's very
easy to build an agent like this using
data from Business Central in Copilot
Studio.
So, how much does it cost? As you know,
licensing in Business Central allows you
to use uh certain power platform tools.
But for Copilot Studio, you need to buy
specific um credits, credit uh packs or
pay as you go uh subscription because
Copilot Studio um is built based on
usage. And then um you don't need to
have any additional paid user licenses
because your users that that you share
the agent with will use and and consume
those credits.
You will find more information about
Copilot Studio and Business Central
under those links. And with that, I
would like to thank you very much.